Mark Ryan Guamos

Software Engineer

Metro Manila, PH

A Senior Software Engineer with 10+ years of professional experience, specializing in fullstack development, Java, SQL, and Javascript. A proven track record of managing large scale software engineering projects to support cloud deployments and integrations.

SKILLS

Backend Frontend DevOps Java Spring Boot SQL JPA Javascript Typescript React Docker Kubernetes CI/CD AWS ArgoCD Hibernate MyBatis Nats Vue Angular **TailwindCSS** Selenium Message Queue Pub/Sub HTML5 Playwright Websocket

Others

Blockchain Solidity Web3

WORK EXPERIENCE (7)

Software Engineer at Amihan Solutions

Jul 2022 - Current

Philippines,

- Responsbile for application maintenance across the codebase.
- Responsbile for adding new features in the application.
- Did application integration with clients and third-party providers.
- Did application support for multiple clients.
- Utilized AWS cloud services.

Software Engineer at Shang Software Solutions

Nov 2017 - Jun 2022

Makati,

- Improved existing applications and fixed concurrency issues.
- Automated processes and regression tests using Selenium/Appium/Playwright.
- Developed monitoring tools.
- Developed online payment gateway (kind of).
- Utilized DevOps tools like CI/CD, Docker, and Kubernetes.
- Participated on migrating on-premise applications to Azure.

Software Engineer at Yondu, Inc.

Aug 2016 - Oct 2017

- Responsible for application maintenance and SQL optimizations.
- Mentored some developers on fullstack development.
- Did application revamp.

- Led a small team of developers.
- Developed a Legal Case Management System for a gov't agency.
- Mentored some junior developers.

Software Engineer at New World Solutions Ltd

Jan 2013 - Nov 2014

- Responsbile for application maintenance across the codebase.
- Responsbile for adding new features in the application.
- Assisted with QA testing.

Software Engineer at ODGS

Jan 2012 - Jan 2013

Makati,

- Responsbile for application maintenance across the codebase.
- Responsbile for adding new features in the application.
- Did application support.

Software Engineer at AATi Technologies

Nov 2010 - Sep 2011

- Helped with small bug fixes while learning Java and several Java frameworks.
- Developed a small tool that parses handwritten values in a scanned form using OCR.

EDUCATION (1)

Bachelor of Science Information Technology at International Electronics and Technical Institue

2006 - 2010

INTERESTS

